Tobi Oladipupo Alabi

Frontend Developer (React.JS)

★ http://tobialabi.netlify.app

https://www.twitter.com/AlabiTobi0140

PROFILE

As a proficient skilled Frontend Developer with 2 years of experience, I am seeking a challenging role where I can apply my expertise in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.JS, and other related technologies to create visually stunning and highly functional websites.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jnr. Frontend Developer, King Cabana

2022 - 2023

- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to design and develop responsive and user-friendly websites.
- Implemented and optimized local storage, JSON server, and other UI components solution.
- Create and maintain reusable UI components using React.
- Write clean, maintainable, and scalable code using HTML, CSS, React.JS, and JavaScript.
- Integrate endpoints from the front end to the back end.
- I developed new features and improved the website's design and usability.

Tech Stack: React.JS, JavaScript, HTML, and Styled-Component CSS.

React Developer (Freelancer), Dream Project

2022

- Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following react.js workflows.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

Tech Stack: React.JS, JavaScript, HTML, and Tailwind CSS

Frontend Developer (Freelancer), Sendchamp

2021 - 2022

- Implement SEO best practices to improve website visibility and conduct website testing and bug fixing.
- Optimize website performance by minimizing page load times and reducing HTTP requests.
- Connection of GitHub branch to other developed code and solved the merge conflict code base.
- Tech Stack: React.JS, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

SKILLS

Database (MySql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB) | **Programming Languages** (Java, Python, JavaScript)

Web Technologies (HTML, CSS, Material UI, Chakra UI, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Styled Component, SASS, and SCSS)

Software Design (OOP(Object Oriented Programming), Git, Design Pattern, ES6, JSX, Node + npm, Critical Thinking)

Framework (React.JS, Node.js) | Methodologies (Jira, SEO, Agile, TDD)

PROJECTS

http://eventapp.netlify.app

http://enquires.netlify.app

https://alabitobi.github.io/gymnastics-app

EDUCATION

Business Management, University of Reading (Henley Business School)	2022 – 2022
Certificate of Software Engineer, Semicolon Africa	2022 – 2022
NYSC Certificate, National Youth Certificate Corps	2018 – 2019
Bachelor of Science and Education, Olabisi Onabanjo University	2013 – 2017